ioption.com 2013-06-05

# Privacy

Your privacy is important to iOption. We recognize the importance of protecting personal information and so we take the maintaining of our trader’s privacy and security very seriously.

Please take a moment to familiarize yourself with our policy and let us know if you have any questions.

The provisions of this notice apply to both former and current customers.

1.    Personal Information

In order to provide you with the very best service, when you apply to become an iOption customer or open a live account, we will ask you for personal information. This information will assist us in evaluating your financial experience, processing your requests and transactions, retrieving lost passwords, keeping you informed about products and services that may be of interest to you, and providing you with a better customer experience. We are also required by law to retain some records.

2.    Required Information May Include:

Application Information – full name, address, birth date, identity or social security number, occupation, assets and income, and other similar information, as detailed on the application forms.

Transaction Information – Information about your transactions with us and/or our affiliates, and records of past communications. These may include your account balances, trading activity, past inquiries and our responses. 

Verification Information – This may be required to verify your identity, and may include passport or driver’s license, utility bill, bank statement, credit card copy etc. 

Note: Anti-Money Laundering ("AML") regulations requires financial institutions to collect information and take action where necessary, in order to verify a customer’s identity. 

Note: iOption will not knowingly collect or maintain personal information from children under 18. If we become aware that a person under 18 has provided us with Personal Information, we will take steps to delete such information from our files.   
If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided us with Personal Information without their consent, he or she should contact us at [support@ioption.com](mailto:support@ioption.com). 

3.    The Use of Cookies

iOption also collects and uses information acquired from "cookies”. "Cookies" are bits of textual information that are sent electronically from a web server to your browser and are stored on your computer. They do not identify you individually nor do they contain personal information about you, unless you have identified yourself or provided the information by, for example, opening an account or registering for an on-line service. iOption may use cookies to measure and identify website traffic patterns and to track the performance of web features and advertisements.   
By providing iOption with a better understanding of how you and others use iOption's websites and other web services, cookies enable iOption to improve the navigation and functionality of its websites and to present the most useful information and offers to you. 

iOption may share information obtained from cookies with its employees, agents and affiliates, but does not sell such information to unaffiliated third parties.

iOption may permit other companies or their third party ad servers to set their own cookies on your browser when you visit iOption´s website. Such companies generally use these cookies as we do, but you should refer to their privacy policies in case of any doubt

4.    Sharing Information

a)    Affiliates

We may share some or all of the personal information described above with our affiliates in order to service client accounts or inform clients of new products and services. Our affiliates may include companies controlled or owned by us, as well as companies which have an ownership interest in our company. Our affiliates will maintain the privacy of your information in the same manner and to the same extent as iOption, and in accordance with this privacy policy.

b)    Third Parties

iOption does not disclose your personal information to third parties, except as described in this privacy policy. Third party disclosures may include sharing such information with non-affiliated companies that perform support services for your account or facilitate your transactions with iOption. These companies may include those that provide professional, legal or accounting services to iOption. Non-affiliate companies that assist iOption in providing services are required to maintain the confidentiality of such information to the extent they receive it. In addition, they are obligated to use your personal information only in the course of providing such services and only for the purposes dictated by iOption.

iOption may disclose a customer’s personal information to a third party in order to fulfill their instructions or pursuant to express consent. It is important to us that you know that iOption will not sell your personal information.

c)    Regulators

iOption may disclose your personal information to third parties as permitted by, or in order to comply with applicable laws and regulations. This may include disclosing personal information in order to cooperate with regulatory authorities and law enforcement agencies, as may be necessary to protect our property or rights.

d)    Merger or Bankruptcy

In the event of a merger of iOption, the company’s customer information will merge along with the company. In the event of bankruptcy, different legal statuses shall apply in accordance with its incorporation laws and its recordkeeping requirements. 

e)    Payment Information

iOption does not keep, in any form, customer’s credit cards information. 

5.    Failure to Provide Personal Information

You have a choice to supply any or all of the personal information required. However, missing information may result in our being unable to open or maintain your account and /or to provide you with our services.

6.    Opt Out 

Should you choose to have your name and personal data removed from our database, you can do so by sending an email to [support@ioption.com](mailto:support@ioption.com), but kindly note that missing information may result in our being unable to open or maintain your account and /or to provide you with our services.

7.    Amendments 

Any amendments to our privacy policy that affect the personal information of users collected on our website will be notified to the users, within a reasonable time, via email. Users will have a choice whether or not we use the information in a different manner. Any amendments made by us that do not affect personal information will be posted on our website.

8.    Mailing Information

Whether you wish to talk to us about our privacy policy or any other issue, the professional team at iOption is available to assist you 24/7. Please feel free to contact us via e-mail, phone, fax and mailing address. You can also or use our chat facility to IM a customer service representative.

Mailing Address:

• Fax:   
• Tel:   
• E-mail: [support@ioption.com](mailto:support@ioption.com)

This Privacy Policy is in effect from 01.04.2013.
